thefilter.com 2007-12-10

# The Filter - Privacy Policy

... 

|  |    |  |    |    | 

|  |   |  |  |   
---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
| 

|  |  |   
---|---|---  
| Privacy Policy  
---  
This privacy policy covers the collection and use of personal information that Exabre Limited, the owner of The Filter, may collect and interact with The Filter, such as when you visit our website or when you call our support associates.   
Please take a moment to read the following to learn more about our information practices, including what type of information is gathered, how the information is used and for what purposes, to whom we disclose the information, and how we safeguard your personal information. Your privacy is a priority at Exabre, and we go to great lengths to protect it.  
Why we collect personal information   
Why do we collect your personal information? We do this for two reasons:  
1\. Because your personal information is necessary for us to deliver a superior level of product functionality and customer service. The Filter product thrives off the ability to collect, analyze, compare and recommend the best music tracks and artists for you. It enables us to give you convenient access to our products and services.   
2\. In addition, your personal information helps us keep you posted on the latest product announcements, and software updates that you might like to hear about.   
3\. In order to improve our service/offer additional functionality in the future.   
Your personal information, such as username/password and music collection data are all we need on an ongoing basis to provide you with our The Filter product and services.  
We also ask you to give us some additional information in your profile page to help us improve our service and understand our customers better. Please take a minute to fill in 'My Profile' when you sign in to the website.  
What information we collect   
There are a number of situations in which your personal information may help us give you better service. For example, we may ask for your personal information when you're discussing a service issue on the phone with an associate, downloading a software update, or registering your product. At such times, we may collect personal information relevant to the situation, such as your name, mailing address, phone number, email address, and contact preferences, information about The Filter product you own, such as the version, and date of download; and information relating to a support or service issue.  
We also collect information regarding customer activities on our website and on related websites. This helps us to determine how best to provide useful information to customers and to understand which parts of our websites and Internet services are of most interest to them.  
  
The Filter allows you to create a Filter ID based on your personal information. This convenient registration process saves you time and allows for easier use of our web services.   
We may use information about your collection as a collective community but this will be done anonymously. For example 15 people have Agadoo in their collection may be displayed on the website (I hope you're not one of them!)   
We also ask for other information regarding your demographics and ask you to choose an online store etc for your convenience and for the reasons above. This information is not shared with anyone but used for your benefit and profiling of our userbase.   
Here's how it works:   
You create a personal profile providing your password and username. The system saves your information and assigns you a personal Filter ID.   
This unique Filter ID is all we need to recognize you on our Music Community Server and enable us to analyze your music collection, safe store and anonymously share your playlists and provide you with the full functionality of The Filter. Your Filter ID does not store any other personal details.  
When we disclose your information  
Exabre takes your privacy very seriously. Be assured that Exabre does not sell or rent your contact information to other marketers. To help us provide superior service, your personal information may be shared with legal entities within the Exabre group globally who will safeguard it in accordance with Exabre's privacy policy. There are also times when it may be advantageous for Exabre to make certain personal information about you available to companies that Exabre has a strategic relationship with or that perform work for Exabre to provide products and services to you on our behalf. These companies may help us process information, extend credit, fulfill customer orders, deliver products to you, manage and enhance customer data, provide customer service or assess your interest in our products and services. These companies are also obligated to protect your personal information in accordance with Exabre's policies. Without such information being made available, it would be difficult for you to have products delivered to you, receive customer service, provide us feedback to improve our products and services, or access certain services, offers, and content on The Filter website.  
At times we may be required by law or litigation to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is absolutely necessary.  
How we protect your personal information  
Exabre takes precautions including administrative, technical, and physical measures to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as un-authorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.  
You can help us by also taking precautions to protect your personal data when you are on the Internet. Change your passwords often using a combination of letters and numbers, and make sure you use a secure web browser.  
Integrity of your personal information  
Exabre has safeguards in place to keep your personal information accurate, complete, and up to date for the purposes for which it is used. Naturally, you always have the right to access and correct the personal information you have provided. You can request a copy of your personal information, your product registration history, and your interactions with The Filter by contacting us at the email address below.  
Cookies and other technologies  
As is standard practice on many corporate websites, The Filter's website may use 'cookies' and other technologies to help us understand which parts of our websites are the most popular, where our visitors are going, and how much time they spend there. We may also use cookies and other technologies to make sure that any online advertising is bringing customers to our products, such as The Filter. We may also use cookies and other technologies to study traffic patterns on our website, to make it even more rewarding as well as to study the effectiveness of our customer communications. Finally, we use cookies to customize your experience and provide greater convenience each time you interact with us.  
As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.  
We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Exabre will not use the information collected to market directly to that person.  
In some of our email messages we use a click-through URL linked to content on The Filter website. When a customer clicks one of these URLs, they pass through our web server before arriving at the destination web page. We track this click-through data to help us determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked simply avoid clicking text or graphic links in the email.  
Our commitment to your privacy  
Exabre takes protecting your privacy very seriously. To make sure your personal information is secure, we communicate these guidelines to our employees and strictly enforce privacy safeguards within the company.  
The Filter's website has links to the sites of other companies. Exabre is not responsible for their privacy practices. We encourage you to learn about the privacy policies of those companies.  
Privacy questions  
If you have questions or concerns about Exabre's Customer Privacy Policy or data processing, please use the email address to contact us. The Filter Administrator will respond to your inquiry within 20 days.  
Exabre may update its privacy policy from time to time. When we change the policy in a material way a notice will be posted on our website along with the updated privacy policy.  
If you have questions or concerns about Exabre's collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information, please email us at support@thefilter.com
